

CONTACT

- San Antonio TX US
- thiyagarajan.angappan@gmail.com
- 1-210-862-6727
- % https://thiyagarajan-angappan.github.io/
- https://github.com/ thiyagarajan-angappan
- in https://www.linkedin.com/ in/ thiyagarajan-
- https://twitter.com/ UndefObject

EDUCATION

3.72

Bachelor of Engineering, Anna University 2001 - 2005

SKILLS

Frontend Development

JavaScript ReactJS SpringMVC HTML5/CSS3

Backend Development

Java RESTful Services NodeJS JPA Hibernate

MSSQL

Build
Gradle CI/CD Git Openshift

Methodologies

Agile Test Driven Development

IDE

VSCode Intellij Eclipse

Tools

Postman SOAP UI

THIYAGARAJAN ANGAPPAN

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

SUMMARY

Full stack engineer aimed at achieving the best solutions in the world of business problems. With over 13 years of experience in design and development of Web Applications, a **curious mind** towards researching and learning emerging technologies, I invest in **self growth** and guide others to reach their best

EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

HCL America Inc | https://www.hcltech.com/geo-presence/united-states | Jul 2018 - Present

Leading a team of 3 senior programmers, planned, designed and implemented software applications. Understand problem statements and business needs of the customer and design the best solutions

- Created a web portal aimed at maintainig and monitoring vendor services.
- Successfully prototyped the **implementation of ELK stack** for vendor services
- Designed enhanced SOAP UI portal for statistics and validation
- Averted missing deadline by **fixing a major bug** in dozer mapping during websphere migration effort

SENIOR CONSULTANT

Openlink Financial LLC | https://openlink.com/ | Aug 2015 - Jun 2018 (2 years 10 months)

Engaged and discussed with traders to understand their day to day activities, identified potential tasks to automate, reduced manual intervention and increased productivity

- Designed and programmed master data compatible with various ways of report generation
- Improved Quarterly report time taken to complete by 70 to 80 percent
- Handled bundling, delivery and installation of completed software in customer systems

ASSISTANT CONSULTANT

TATA Consultancy Service Ltd | https://www.tcs.com/ | Nov 2006 - Aug 2015 (8 years 9 months)

Worked with a team of 2 senior programmers onsite, 2 in mexico and 10 in India, translated business needs to technical tasks and helped replace mainframe screens to web based applications

- Mentored / trained team members in technologies used and processes followed in project delivery
- Improved time to market by 30% in the implementation of UX changes
- Pioneered the design and implementation of esign integration for insurance products

$\ V\ O\ L\ U\ N\ T\ E\ E\ R$

FRONTEND ENGINEER

ClimateMind | https://climatemind.org/ | Jun 2020 - Present

Group of tech guys, concerned and alarmed about climate change and would like to provide a platform, a conversation started to help those who are undecided about climate change and its dreadful impacts

AWARDS

- Cyberark Certified Trustee | Sep 2019 | CyberArk
- Distinguished Achiever | Sep 2019 | HCL America Inc
- Technical Excellence | Jun 2013 | TATA Consultancy Services Ltd

LANGUAGES

- Tamil
- English

INTERESTS

- Algorithms

 Leetcode
 Hackerrank
 Codechef
 Javascript
- Photography
 Portraiture Fashion Landscape
- Running
- Running

 | 5k | Morning runs | Trail runs |